<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<articlelist>
  <article>
    <link>href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1570023217301654"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/012jiangguoting.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Cross-platform metabolomics investigating the intracellular metabolic alterations of HaCaT cells exposed to phenanthrene</title>
    <journal>Journal of Chromatography B</journal>
    <author>images/members/jiangguoting.jpg</author>
    <name>蒋果廷</name>
    <DOI>10.1016/j.jchromb.2017.05.023</DOI>
    <PMID></PMID>
    <keywords>Metabolomics; Cross-platform; HaCaT cells; Phenanthrene</keywords>
    <abstract>Phenanthrene (Phe) is one of the most abundant Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) contamination from various ambient sources, which has a tremendous impact on public health. However, our knowledge regarding its effects on skin remains limited. In this study, we investigated the metabolite profiling of the human keratinocytes HaCaT cells after Phe exposure to understand the toxic effects of Phe exposure on skin. To obtain a broad picture of metabolome with various hydrophilicity, a cross-platform approach with GC–MS and UHPLC–QTOF-MS has been employed. Data were analyzed by multivariate statistical analysis and samples were separated successfully using supervised PLS-DA models. It was shown that the impacts of Phe exposure on HaCaT cells were both dose-related and time-related. A total of 48 Phe-regulated metabolites were identified and among which 19 were confirmed by reference standards. By pathway analysis, amino acid metabolism, glutathione metabolism and glycerophospholipid metabolism were highlighted as the major metabolic pathways disturbed by Phe. Furthermore, it was found that the mechanisms included a reduced amino pool and a reduced antioxidant status. Overall, these results aid in improving understanding of the dermal toxicology related to Phe, and demonstrate this cross-platform approach is suitable for metabolomics researches on HaCaT cells.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27564527"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/011kanghongyan.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Exploration of candidate biomarkers for human psoriasis based on gas chromatography-mass spectrometry serum metabolomics.</title>
    <journal>British Journal of Dermatology</journal>
    <author>images/members/kanghongyan.jpg</author>
    <name>康宏艳</name>
    <DOI>10.1111/bjd.15008</DOI>
    <PMID>27564527</PMID>
    <keywords></keywords>
    <abstract>BACKGROUND: Recent studies have shown that dysregulated metabolic pathways are linked to psoriasis pathogenesis. However, an extensive, unbiased metabolic analysis in patients with psoriasis has not been completely explored. The metabolome represents the end products of proteomics or cellular processes that may be closely associated with the pathogenesis of psoriasis. OBJECTIVES: To determine the differences in serum metabolomic profiles among patients with psoriasis and healthy controls with the goal of identifying potential biomarkers in patients with psoriasis. MATERIALS AND METHODS: Serum metabolomic profiles from 29 subjects (14 patients with psoriasis and 15 sex- and age-matched healthy controls). The serum metabolites were analysed by gas chromatography-mass spectrometry based on a combined full scan and selected-ion monitoring mode. RESULTS: Multivariate statistical analysis of metabolomics data revealed altered serum metabolites between the patients with psoriasis and healthy individuals. Compared with healthy individuals, patients with psoriasis had higher levels of amino acids including asparagine, aspartic acid, isoleucine, phenylalanine, ornithine and proline; higher levels of lactic acid and urea; and lower levels of crotonic acid, azelaic acid, ethanolamine and cholesterol. CONCLUSIONS: It appears that the glycolysis pathway and amino acid metabolic activity are increased in patients with psoriasis. These metabolic perturbations may stem from increased demand for protein biosynthesis and keratinocyte hyperproliferation. Our findings may help to elucidate the pathogenesis of psoriasis and provide insights into early diagnosis and therapeutic intervention.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25544010"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/010lixia.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>A sensitive method for digoxin determination using formate-adduct ion based on the effect of ionization enhancement in liquid chromatograph-mass spectrometer.</title>
    <journal>Journal of Chromatography B</journal>
    <author>images/members/lixia.jpg</author>
    <name>李霞</name>
    <DOI>10.1016/j.jchromb.2014.11.023</DOI>
    <PMID>25544010</PMID>
    <keywords>Digoxin; Formate-adduct; LC/MS/MS; Rat plasma; Sensitivity</keywords>
    <abstract>A sensitive and rapid method based on formate-adduct ion detection was developed and fully validated for digoxin determination in rat plasma. For LC/MS/MS detection with formate-adducts as precursor ions, transitions of &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;z&lt;/em&gt; 825.5→779.9 for digoxin and &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;z&lt;/em&gt; 809.5→763.4 for the internal standard (digitoxin) were monitored in negative mode. To investigate the impact of formic acid on the mass response and method sensitivity, a formic acid concentration range of 0-0.1% (0, 0.0005%, 0.002%, 0.01%, 0.1%, v/v) was evaluated. A concentration of 0.002% gave the highest sensitivity, which was 16- to 18-fold higher than deprotonated ions, and was designated as the contribution giving the strongest ionization enhancement and adduction. A number of parameters were then varied in order to optimize the method, and a limit of quantitation (LOQ) at 0.2 ng/mL was reached with an injection volume of 5 μL, a total run time of 3 min, and 0.1 mL of rat plasma. A calibration curve was plotted over the range 0.2-50 ng/mL (&lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;=0.9998), and the method was successfully applied to study pharmacokinetics in rat following a single oral administration of digoxin (0.05 mg/kg). Four additional steroid saponins (digitoxin, deslanoside, ginsenoside Rg1 and Rb1) were investigated to assess the impact of formic acid on the mass response of steroid saponins. Compounds with a conjugated lactonic ring in their structures such as digoxin, digitoxin and deslanoside tended to form stable formate-adduct ions more easily. The LC/MS/MS method developed here is therefore well suited for the quantification of steroid saponins that are difficult to deprotonate using other MS approaches.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25041011"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/009zhouqingyuan.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Metabolics Investigation of Cutaneous T Cell Lymphpma Based on UHPLC-QTOF/MS.</title>
    <journal>Asian Pacific journal of cancer prevention</journal>
    <author>images/members/zhouqingyuan.jpg</author>
    <name>周清源</name>
    <DOI></DOI>
    <PMID>25041011</PMID>
    <keywords>Cutaneous T cell lymphoma; metabolomics; Biomarkers; UHPLC-QTOF/MS</keywords>
    <abstract>OBJECTIVES:The identification of cutaneous T cell lymphoma (CTCL) biomarkers may serve as a predictor of disease progression and treatment response. The aim of this study was to map potential biomarkers in CTCL plasma. DESIGN AND METHODS:Plasma metabolic perturbations between CTCL cases and healthy individuals were investigated using metabolomics and ultrahigh performance liquid chromatography–quadrupole time-of-flight mass spectrometry (UHPLC-QTOF/MS). RESULTS:Principal component analysis (PCA) of the spectra showed clear metabolic changes between the two groups. Thirty six potential biomarkers associated with CTCL were found. CONCLUSIONS:Based on PCA, several biomarkers were determined and further identified by LC/MS/MS analysis. All of these could be potential early markers of CTCL. In addition, we established that heparin as anticoagulant has better pre-treatment results than EDTA with the UHPLC-QTOF/MS approach.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24812693"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/008liuxiaoyun.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Rapid separation and identification of Strychnos alkaloids metabolites in rats by ultra high performance liquid chromatography with linear ion trap Orbitrap mass spectrometry.</title>
    <journal>Journal of Separation Science</journal>
    <author>images/members/liuxiaoyun.jpg</author>
    <name>刘晓云</name>
    <DOI>10.1002/jssc.201301055</DOI>
    <PMID>24812693</PMID>
    <keywords>High-Resolution mass spectrometry; Metabolite identification; Rat urine; Strychnos alkaloids</keywords>
    <abstract>An &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; study of Strychnos alkaloids metabolites in rats by ultra high performance liquid chromatography with linear ion trap Orbitrap MS is reported for the first time. Two major Strychnos alkaloids compounds including strychnine and brucine were investigated. To obtain optimal extraction efficiency, samples were pretreated by using an SPE plate. The structures of metabolites and their fragment ions were characterized based on the accurate mass and MS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; data. Forty-seven metabolites were identified in rat urine, of which 25 were reported for the first time. Four new metabolism pathways were proposed on the basis of the identified metabolites. This study provides a practical approach for rapidly identifying complicated metabolites, a methodology that could be widely applied not only in forensic and clinically toxicological relevant cases, but also for the structural characterization of metabolites of other compounds.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23483744"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/007dongqixin.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Optimization of mobile phase for the determination of Esomeprazole and related compounds and investigation of stress degradation by LC–MS.</title>
    <journal>Journal of Separation Science</journal>
    <author>images/members/dongqixin.jpg</author>
    <name>董琦鑫</name>
    <DOI>10.1002/jssc.201201114</DOI>
    <PMID>23483744</PMID>
    <keywords>Esomeprazole; Improved separation; LC-MS Characterization; Mechanism; Related compounds</keywords>
    <abstract>In this study, the objective was to investigate the degradation behavior of Esomeprazole under different recommended stress conditions according to International Conference on Harmonization of Technical Requirements for Registration of Pharmaceuticals for Human Use by HPLC. Our research showed that the effect of mobile phase species on separation was significant for the determination of Esomeprazole and its related compounds. Successful separation of the drug from its related impurities and degradation products formed under different stress conditions was achieved using ammonium acetate buffer/ACN by a gradient elution. Compared with phosphate buffer/ACN, ammonium acetate buffer/ACN under same pH and gradient showed a great improvement in resolution due to the change of elution order. The drug was subjected to stress conditions including acidic, alkaline, oxidative, photolytic, and thermal conditions. Extensive degradation occurred in acidic and oxidative conditions, while mild degradation was observed in alkaline and photolytic conditions. Besides, it turned out the drug was extremely stable under thermal condition. The stability-indicating LC-UV method was validated with respect to linearity, precision, accuracy, specificity, and robustness. The LC-MS method was also adopted for the characterization of degradation products. Based on the &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;z&lt;/em&gt; values and fragmentation patterns, the degradation pathway of the drug has been proposed.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22997096"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/006yuzhuhong.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Simultaneous determination of six toxic alkaloids in human plasma and urine using capillary zone electrophoresis coupled to time-of-flight mass spectrometry.</title>
    <journal>Journal of Separation Science</journal>
    <author>images/members/yuzhuhong.jpg</author>
    <name>余祝宏</name>
    <DOI>10.1002/jssc.201200263</DOI>
    <PMID>22997096</PMID>
    <keywords>Alkaloids; Capillary electrophoresis coupled to time-of-flight mass spectrometry; Plasma; Solid-phase extraction; Urine</keywords>
    <abstract>A novel capillary zone electrophoresis separation coupled to electro spray ionization time-of-flight mass spectrometry method was developed for the simultaneous analysis of six toxic alkaloids: brucine, strychnine, atropine sulfate, anisodamine hydrobromide, scopolamine hydrobromide and anisodine hydrobromide in human plasma and urine. To obtain optimal sensitivity, a solid-phase extraction method using Oasis MCX cartridges (1 mL, 30 mg; Waters, USA) for the pretreatment of samples was used. All compounds were separated by capillary zone electrophoresis at 25 kV within 12 min in an uncoated fused-silica capillary of 75 μm id × 100 cm and were detected by time-of-flight mass spectrometry. This method was validated with regard to precision, accuracy, sensitivity, linear range, limit of detection (LOD), and limit of quantification (LOQ). In the plasma and urine samples, the linear calibration curves were obtained over the range of 0.50-100 ng/mL. The LOD and LOQ were 0.2-0.5 ng/mL and 0.5-1.0 ng/mL, respectively. The intra- and interday precision was better than 12% and 13%, respectively. Electrophoretic peaks could be identified by mass analysis.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1387380612002606"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/005linzhiyan.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Structural characterization and identification of five triterpenoid saponins isolated from Momordica cochinchinensis extracts by liquid chromatography/tandem mass spectrometry.</title>
    <journal>International Journal of Mass Spectrometry</journal>
    <author>images/members/linzhiyan.jpg</author>
    <name>林志燕</name>
    <DOI>10.1016/j.ijms.2012.07.022</DOI>
    <PMID></PMID>
    <keywords>Identification; Momordica cochinchinensis; LC/MSn; Saponins</keywords>
    <abstract>In this work, we reported the use of high-performance liquid chromatography (HPLC) with electrospray ionization multi-stage tandem mass spectrometry (ESI-MS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) to study the characterization of five triterpenoid saponins from &lt;em&gt;Momordica cochinchinensis&lt;/em&gt; extracts in positive ion mode and negative ion mode, revealed the fragmentation behavior of these five &lt;em&gt;M. cochinchinensis&lt;/em&gt; saponins in different ion modes. Results showed that in negative ion mode, fragmentation on the &lt;em&gt;M. cochinchinensis&lt;/em&gt; triterpenoid saponins at positions C28 and O bond were the primary pathways. In positive ion mode, the predominant diagnostic ions were a series of ions resulting from the rupture of the saccharic chain on C28. Comparison of different fragmentation patterns showed that the results from positive and negative ion ESI MS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; were complementary. Both modes can yield structurally different information for the characterization of triterpenoid saponins. This study provides a powerful method for the online structural identification of five triterpenoid saponins from &lt;em&gt;M. cochinchinensis&lt;/em&gt;, and some of which have not been reported.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1365/s10337-010-1672-0"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/004panle.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>An LC–MS Method for a Hexokinase Inhibitor Study Based on Adenosine 50-Triphosphate Determination and Application to the Anticancer Mechanism of Momordica cochinchinensis.</title>
    <journal>Chromatographia</journal>
    <author>images/members/panle.jpg</author>
    <name>潘乐</name>
    <DOI>10.1365/s10337-010-1672-0</DOI>
    <PMID></PMID>
    <keywords>Column liquid chromatography–mass spectrometry; Hexokinase inhibitor; Adenosine 5′-triphosphate; Momordica cochinchinensis</keywords>
    <abstract>A reliable and validated LC–MS method was established for a hexokinase inhibitor study based on adenosine 5′-triphosphate (ATP) determination. By adding 5 mM ammonium acetate in the aqueous phase, this method enabled the determination of ATP by LC–MS and greatly increased the MS signal of ATP. This method was used in the study of the anticancer mechanism of &lt;em&gt;Momordica cochinchinensis&lt;/em&gt;, an exact ingredient which had exhibited certain hexokinase inhibitor activity. This might reveal the anticancer mechanism of &lt;em&gt;Momordica cochinchinensis&lt;/em&gt;.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1365/s10337-010-1683-x"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/003panle.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Simultaneous Determination of Levodopa, Benserazide and 3-O-Methyldopa in Human Serum by LC–MS–MS.</title>
    <journal>Chromatographia</journal>
    <author>images/members/panle.jpg</author>
    <name>潘乐</name>
    <DOI>10.1365/s10337-010-1683-x</DOI>
    <PMID></PMID>
    <keywords>Column liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry; Levodopa; Benserazide; 3-O-methyldopa</keywords>
    <abstract>For the first time a sensitive, specific and rapid LC–MS–MS assay is presented for the simultaneous determination of levodopa (L-DP), 3-&lt;em&gt;O&lt;/em&gt;-methyldopa (3-OMD) and benserazide (BSZ) in human serum. The three compounds were extracted from human serum by protein precipitation followed by dilution of the supernatant with aqueous formic acid. In serum, linearity was observed between 50 and 1,000 ng mL&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; of L-DP, 3-OMD and BSZ, respectively. Intra-day and inter-day RSD values were below 10.56 and 6.22% at concentrations of 120, 360 and 720 ng mL&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;. The presented method showed excellent specificity and sensitivity compared with other methods reported. It was applied to a pharmacokinetic study and demonstrated its applicability to pre-clinical and clinical pharmacological research.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19159890"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/002sushengmin.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>Online preconcentration of recombinant Arg-Gly-Asp-hirudin using dynamic pH junction for analysis in human urine samples by capillary electrophoresis-mass spectrometry.</title>
    <journal>Journal of Chromatography A</journal>
    <author>images/members/sushengmin.jpg</author>
    <name>苏圣民</name>
    <DOI>10.1016/j.chroma.2008.12.050</DOI>
    <PMID>19159890</PMID>
    <keywords>CE-MS; Online preconcentration; Dynamic pH junction; rRGD-hirudin; Human urine; Quantitative assay</keywords>
    <abstract>A sensitive and effort-saving method was established and validated for the quantitative determination of recombinant Arg-Gly-Asp-hirudin (rRGD-hirudin) in human urine samples. The assay was performed on a uncoated fused silica capillary of 70 cm x 50 microm I.D. and a positive voltage of 30 kV was applied. The sample was injected under pressure of 50 mbar for 300 s and the temperature of capillary was kept 25 degrees C. Sheath liquid consisting of 30% methanol and 70% of 0.1% formic acid aqueous solution flowing at 7 microL/min was supplied to the CE-electrospray interface. Utilizing the dynamic pH junction technique, a lower limit of quantitation of approximately 35 nM was achieved (concentration coefficiency was about 100-fold) without complex sample preprocessing procedure. CE-MS conditions and parameters were also optimized to obtain better performance. The method has been successfully applied in clinical research of rRGD-hirudin.</abstract>
  </article>
  <article>
    <link>href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18541462"</link>
    <pdf>href="articlePdf/001sushengmin.pdf"</pdf>
    <title>A development of LC–MS method combining ultrafiltration and lyophilization for determination of r-RGD-Hirudin in human serum.</title>
    <journal>Journal of Chromatography B</journal>
    <author>images/members/sushengmin.jpg</author>
    <name>苏圣民</name>
    <DOI>10.1016/j.jchromb.2008.05.032</DOI>
    <PMID>18541462</PMID>
    <keywords>r-RGD-Hirudin; Quantitative assay; LC–MS; Ultrafiltration; Freeze drying; Clinical research</keywords>
    <abstract>A reliable and validated LC-MS method was established for determination of r-RGD-Hirudin in human serum. Ultrafiltration was used instead of liquid-liquid extraction or solid phase extraction for water solubility drug r-RGD-Hirudin extraction. Freeze drying was used for concentration. The experiment conditions, including pre-processing procedure and LC-MS, have been investigated and optimized. Comparing with reported assays, the current method showed significant improvement in specificity, linearity, precision and sensitivity. This method has been successfully applied in clinical research of r-RGD-Hirudin.</abstract>
  </article>
</articlelist>
